Nandeeswari Kuppusamy

(201) 565-7087 knandhu.27@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> San Francisco / Bay Area

Skills Node.js, JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3, Git, PostgreSQL, jQuery

Projects

GetAnswers (React / Redux, Ruby / Rails, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, jQuery, Webpack) <u>Live Site</u> | <u>Github</u> A web app inspired by Stack Overflow, where professionals can ask questions with tags and post answers in rich text format and search questions based on title and tags.

- Applied customized design and functionality to the react-quill library for smooth user experience in rich text editing.
- Implemented custom back end and front end user authentication by combining Rails conventions, Active Record, and customized React-Router higher order components.
- Optimized database usage and eliminated N+1 queries by observing SQL and Active Record best practices.

Ingredish (React, Express, Node.js, HTML5, CSS, MongoDB)

<u>Live Site</u> | <u>Github</u>

A web app to search food recipes based on the user entered ingredients, implemented search feature with exact match of ingredients provided by the user.

- Adhered to React and ES6 best practices to generate a true single page reactive web app experience.
- Created custom modal framework using React component architecture allowing for efficient development of new forms.
- Designed asynchronous/await functions utilizing AXIOS API calls to fetch user request data from multiple collections.
- Used Mongoose populate method to fetch underlying related data across multiple collections.

RockNRoll (JavaScript, 3.js, HTML5, CSS)

<u>Live Site</u> | <u>Github</u>

A 3D animation game which interests users with an endless runner concept.

- Decreased graphic rendering lag through the use of HTML5 Canvas and animation frames, resulting in a more realistic gaming experience.
- Engineered layers of gaming complexity through the introduction of game state changes that rely on OOP techniques and vector calculations.
- Implemented user interaction by adding a listener to the document to look for keyboard events and made seamless user experience.

Experience

Teachscape Inc.

QA Engineer

Jul 2015 - Jun 2016

- Wrote test scripts to test web application and achieved 90% test coverage, resulting in bug free launch.
- Implemented Automation test suites using Page Objects, Data Driven framework using Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, IntelliJ.

Kaiser Permanente

ETL Tester

Oct 2014 - May 2015

- Extensively used Oracle to write complex SQL queries to validate data between source and target tables
- Reporting bugs and track defects using QC ALM.

Education

App Academy Oct 2019 - Feb 2020 - Immersive software development course on full stack web development. **Anna University** Aug 2006 - Jun 2012 - Bachelor's & Master's in Information Technology